<dashboard>
  <label>Schema</label>
  <description/>
  <row>
    <html>
      <h1>Search Activity Help: Schema</h1>
      
      <h2>Help Contents</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="/app/search_activity/help">Help Home</a></li>
        <li><a href="/app/search_activity/installation">Installation</a></li>
        <li><a href="/app/search_activity/featurelist">Feature List</a></li>
        <li>Schema</li>
    </ul>
      <p>For anyone interested in developing on top of this app, creating your own views, etc., you will find two tsidx namespaces generated 
        via the tscollect command. The parameters available in these namespaces are as follows:
        <ul>
          <li>search_activity.searchhistory - This source of data is fed entirely by the audit.log held normally in index=_audit sourcetype=audittrail
            <ol>
              <li>_time - float - The earliest time found.</li>
              <li>NumExports - int - The number of times a search was exported (by any user -- careful)</li>
              <li>WasShared - "yes"/"no" - Were there hits to the acl rest endpoint and the control rest endpoint, characteristic of sharing a search?</li>
              <li>searchspan - latest minus earliest:
              <ul>
                <li>searchspan_s - int - seconds</li>
                <li>searchspan_m - 1-precision - minutes</li>
                <li>searchspan_h - 1-precision - hours</li>
                <li>searchspan_d - 1-precision - days</li>
              </ul>
              </li>
              <li>total_run_time - int - How long did the search run for?</li>
              <li>result_count - int - How many results were there?</li>
              <li>scan_count - int - How many results were scanned? (Placeholder for a thorough Splunk® answers or blog post, upon demand)</li>
              <li>event_count - int - How many results were brought back off disk?</li>
              <li>Accuracy - float - round((event_count / scan_count) * 100,2). </li>
              <li>searchtype - "adhoc"/"adhoc (subsearch)"/"dashboard"/"dashboard (subsearch)"/"summarization"/"summarization (subsearch)"/"scheduled"/"subsearch (subsearch)"/"realtime" - Type of search (calculated by searchtype eval field in props)</li>
              <li>search_status - "failed"/"completed"/"cancelled"/? - The result of the search. Technically: values(eval(if(info="granted",null,info)))</li>
              <li>savedsearch_name - string - The name of the saved search, if defined</li>
              <li>searchcommands - string - Effectively values(eval(commands(actualsearch))). This is a list of all the commands used in a search (though tscollect doesn't support notating if someone uses eventstats four times in a search, much to my chagrin. At least not without more work.)</li>
              <li>user - string - Username (= sAMAccountName for AD people)</li>
              <!-- <li>name - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the LDAP displayName</li>
              <li>ManagerDN - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the manager's distinguishedName</li>
              <li>email - string - IF doing LDAP, this will be the mail attribute</li>
              <li>description - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the description attribute</li>
              <li>city - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the c attribute</li>
              <li>location - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the l attribute</li>
              <li>organization - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the o attribute (usually referring to some sort of geography, for AD people)</li>
              <li>state - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the st attribute</li>
              <li>title - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the title attribute</li>
              <li>ManagementChain - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the users mvjoin(ManagementChain, "|"). See note on temporality for the LDAP queries and tscollect, below</li>
              <li>ManagerName - string - If doing LDAP, this will be the manager's name.</li>
              <li>NumDirectReports - int - If doing LDAP, this will show how many direct reports the user has</li> -->
              <li>exec_time - int - The exec_time of the search (from the log)</li>
              <li>earliest - float - The earliest_time of the search.</li>
              <li>latest - float - The latest_time of the search.</li>
              <li>actualsearch - string - The full search string.</li>
              <li>Accuracy - float - The ratio of event_count / result_count, represented as a percentage (i.e., n * 100)</li>
              <li>search_et_diff - int - The difference between exec_time and the earliest_time (effectively, going back to -15min or -30d)</li>
              <li>search_lt_diff - int - The difference between exec_time and the latest_time (effectively, starting now or -7d)</li>
              <li>MVSearchCommands - string - A pipe separated list of the search commands for this search. (When using tscollect, 10 multi-valued rex commands become one.) Created with mvjoin(searchcomands, "|"), so feel free to use | makemv MVSearchCommands delim="|". </li>
              <li>WasShared - string - "yes" or "no" indicates whether the ACL endpoint was hit for the search string in the 10-20 minutes after the search completed.</li>
              <li>WasExported - string - "yes" or "no" indicates whether the export endpoint was hit for the search string in the 10-20 minutes after the search completed. This is a pretty bad metric, and will be improved moving forward.</li>
              <li>search_et_diff - int - earliest_time - earliest.</li>
              <li>search_lt_diff - int - earliest_time - latest.</li>
              <li>time_bucket - string - a case statement that puts search_et_diff into different time buckets.</li>
              <li>ShouldInvestigate - int - Are there any telltale signs that this search should be inspected? Defined by the macro `ShouldInvestigate`.</li>
              <li>SearchHead - string - The search head where the search was run.</li>

            </ol>
          </li>
        </ul>
        <ul>
          <li>search_activity.events - This source of data is held mostly in index=_internal, with the logon history pulled from index=_audit
            <ol>
              <li>_time - float - The time of each event.</li>
              <li>date_hour - string - The hour of the day of each event (for convenience).</li>
              <li>type - string - The type of the log. Options are: weblog, manager, scheduler, search_concurrency, login.</li>
              <li>uri_path - string - The URL browsed to for weblogs.</li>
              <li>myapp - string - For weblogs, the app.</li>
              <li>myview - string - For weblogs, the view.</li>
              <li>result - string - For login events, the result.</li>
              <li>user - string - The username of the event.</li>
              <li>active_hist_searches - int - How many historical searches are active at one time (from the search concurrency logs).</li>
              <li>active_realtime_searches - int - How many realtime searches are active at one time (from the search concurrency logs).</li>
              <li>status - string - The status of a scheduled search.</li>
              <li>savedsearch_name - string - The name of a scheduled search.</li>
              <li>mysearch - string - The search string for a scheduled search.</li>
              <li>exported - string - "export" if this event indicates that the search was exported.</li>
              <li>searchid - string - The search ID where appropriate.</li>
              <li>myaction </li>
              <li>result_count - int - The number of results in a search.</li>
              <li>alert_actions - string - The alert ations of a scheduled search.</li>
              <li>result_count - string - How many results came from a scheduled search.</li>
              <li>SearchHead - string - The search head that generated the log.</li>
              <li>actualsearch - string - The search string for audit logs (included in both TSIDX to ease the correlation.. may be more efficient in the future to leverage a lookup that will pull them up).</li>
            </ol>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p>
              
        
      <p>For those interested, there are two primary reasons for utilizing tscollect rather than the generally
        preferable data model acceleration. The first reason is that in the case of the searchhistory report, I wanted to consolidate many 
        logs together and provide one entry per search. Without a preliminary stats, there would be several different logs related to 
        each event, confusing the ability to do counts accurately (would require dc(searchid) instead of count, which isn't intuitive).
        The second, smaller reason, is that the initial customers did not want to impact their environment with distributed tsidx files,
        normally a major benefit, except that it would trigger change control requirements. tscollect allows the data to stay local on
        a admin or dev search head. This works fairly well in this scenario, given the small size of the tsidx namespace for this app.
        </p>
             
    </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>
